Janani Teklur Srinivasa

Data Analyst/Business Analyst
LinkedIn | Website Link | Tableau

Location: Seattle, Washington +1-206-849-1091 | jananibalaji20@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced mainframe developer with 6 years of expertise seeking to transition into a data analyst role. Completed numerous Data Analytics Projects using the skills acquired through certification courses in **Google Data Analytics**, Tableau, Python, R and SQL. Driven by objectives and meticulous in approach, with a deep enthusiasm for extracting actionable insights from intricate datasets.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Tata Consultancy Services

July 2018 - May 2021

IT Analyst

- Utilized data analysis skills to interpret collected data and produce impactful reports for the business, employing SQL and Excel.
- Built several user-facing utilities to update internal control tables, resulting in streamlined processes for internal teams. This led to saving **15**% time during production release and a **50**% reduction in errors.
- Implemented code enhancement, unit testing and integration testing for over 10+ core modules for a project that
 involved fixing the way in which the Key of a core table was created during data entry by end-users leading to a 100%
 reduction in errors reported within the system.

Tata Consultancy Services

System Engineer

June 2015 – June 2018

- Optimized efficiency by automating numerous monthly, daily, and yearly reports, resulting in a **50%** reduction in time required for report creation and data collection.
- Managed production support activities, creation of unit test plan, process documentation and coding with Cobol-Db2, Cobol-CICS and Batch Cobol modules for critical projects in the Banking sector for batch and online programs.

PROJECTS

Doordash Marketing Analysis

• Conducted data cleaning, transformation, analysis, and visualizations for a leading food delivery company and extracted valuable insights to devise marketing strategies for boosting sales using **Excel**.

Spotify Top Songs Analysis

• Analyzed a list of songs released from 2010-2019 from Spotify's dataset and found popular artists, songs, and genre. Derived insights on correlation between aspects like beats per minute, duration, etc. using **R programming.**

Cyclistic Bike Share Analysis Using R

• Performed data cleaning, Transformation, analysis and extracted insights to formulate strategies to enhance a bike share company's performance by converting casual riders to annual members using **R programming and Tableau**.

CERTIFICATIONS

• Data Career Jumpstart Bootcamp

August 2023

Google Data Analytics Certification

March 2023

CGPA: **8.55/10**

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering (Electronics & Communication)

SKILLS

- SQL (MYSQL | SQL Server | Big Query)
- Tableau
- R programming

- Excel (Pivot tables | VLOOKUP | Charting | Conditional formatting)
- Python (Pandas | Matplotlib)